Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Federation sent a Medea squadron
to rescue the heavily damaged White Base...
...but the squadron was attacked
by Goufs and Dodai bombers.
Amuro and the others hurried to assist.
With the help of the G-Parts
designed to power-up the Gundam...
...they succeeded in defeating the enemy.
Black Tri-Star
This is a poor joke.
This plan is absolutely ridiculous!
Have you forgotten how many precious
resources M'Quve has sent us from under...
...the Earth Federation's siege?
Also, the practical
application of mobile armor...
Excuse me. But the authority
of the military would be ruined.
A man's honor?! Military authority?!
These things can be sacrificed
for Zeon victory!
We'll save your honor once we win this war.
Deliver the mobile suits for close combat
on Earth to Commander Char.
But, Your Highness, we can't do it right away.
Of course not!
Just get them to Char before
he joins the Mad Angler squadron.
Also, I'm sure there are heavy mobile suits
allocated to other units...
...that can be used for combat on Earth.
We should consider
sending those over too.
Yes, ma'am!
Have you sent Doms to
the Tri-Stars?
Yes. They should have already left
satellite orbit to rendezvous with M'Quve.
Good. Keep an eye on the situation
and respond accordingly.
As the occupier of the Moon...
...Kycilia could not join
the battle on Earth in person.
The fighting was unsettled on all fronts.
The best she could do
was to assist M'Quve...
...by sending her own brave warriors
known as "Zeon's Tri-Stars".
Good morning.
Huh? G-Good morning, Lt. Matilda!
What are these?
Components for the Gundam's
power-up parts.
I'll have to do the repairs myself,
so I was organizing them.
That's impressive.
Where are you going?
Up to the bridge.
I'll show you the way.
No, that's fine.
I'm pretty resourceful! I know a shortcut.
All right.
Oh. Good morning!
Good morning.
Amuro!
What's the big idea?!
You promised me...
...you'd fix the air conditioner in my room
once you finished breakfast.
Oh really?
Hmph!
Hmph! Hmph! Hmph!
Quit it!
That Ms. Matilda. She's just my type.
She's elegant. And she's so nice, too.
I'd be a happy man
if I had a girlfriend like Ms. Matilda.
Idle hands make mischief.
Huh?
Ah! Good morning! L-Lieutenant!
Good luck finding an elegant girlfriend.
L-Lieutenant!
Now that I've made a total fool of myself...
I'd like to ask for permission to take
a picture of you and myself!
No problem, as long as we do it now.
Yes! ...I'm honored!
Would you guys give me a break?!
This only gives me 12 copies per photo!
C'mon, Kai!
Let me in, too!
Okay, I'm taking the picture! ...There!
Mr. Bright. I've brought Lt. Matilda to you.
Thank you.
No. Please don't get up.
I'm terribly sorry, Lieutenant.
You look better than I expected.
Excuse me.
All right!
Our forces are progressing too slowly...
...especially since I want to move up
Operation Odessa.
Elran. Tell them to hurry and rendezvous.
Yes, sir! However...
"However"? In the military,
there is only action. Isn't that right?
Sir!
General Revil.
An Air Force patrol team has sent us
a report they caught.
A Zeon Zanzibar warship
has come down to Earth?
Our Big Tray has already
confirmed that information.
No. Look at what it says after that.
The Black Tri-Stars were dispatched
with their new mobile suits.
They're the ones who captured me
at the Battle of Loum.
They're very tough.
We've got to begin Odessa Day earlier
than we had anticipated. Right, Elran?
What?! Yes, I'll inform
all units at once!
You're looking a bit pale.
Judock. You'd better not be spying
for both sides.
Revil is quite aware that the Black Tri-Stars
have landed in a Zanzibar.
B-But that just can't be.
Tell M'Quve that Operation Odessa
will be commencing sooner.
Will we be able to finish
ahead of schedule, Colonel?
Yes... That's no problem.
Amuro. The Gundam's power-up parts.
Right!
Ms. Matilda...
Yes?
Why did you join the Supply Corps?
Let's see...
Amid all the destruction of war...
...it enables me to create things.
Create things?
While wars only bring destruction...
...I felt that human beings
need more than that to go on living.
And we're clean now.
Ms. Matilda.
I believe...
I believe that you're a strong person,
Ms. Matilda.
How cheeky.
I-I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
Yeah! Leave them to us!
We're a whole different class than Char.
Now, show us the Trojan Horse
and this so-called white mobile suit.
Well, whatever...
Ortega, Mash! Let's go!
Yeah!
We're getting close.
No metallic reaction detected...
We're jumping to the next mountain!
What is it?!
Enemy spotted. 3 mobile suits...
...approaching from 2 o'clock.
Prepare to intercept. Mirai, take charge.
Yes, sir!
- It's the enemy!
- The enemy's coming!
All right! All clear!
Move Medea No. 3 out of
the White Base's path!
I'm glad the controls are up here now...
But can I really operate this by myself?
Hey, Hayato! Are you all right there?
If you can work yours by yourself,
Mr. Kai, then I'll be fine too.
They're past our second surveillance net.
They're moving quickly.
Is the Gundam ready to go yet?
That's the problem...
They're still checking the G-Armor.
I was just told they need me down there!
By whom?!
Engineering Colonel Seki.
He wants me to operate the G-Fighter.
What?! Can't Job John do it?
He's a pilot too.
I have experience with mobile suits.
I see... Let's have Fraw Bow
take over your position for now.
Ms. Mirai!
The engine's just been overhauled.
Don't forget to do a trial run.
Understood!
Okay, Fraw Bow. Please take over.
I'm off.
The computer takes care of the connection,
so the pilot doesn't have to worry about it.
But what if the computer gets damaged?
If the laser sensors are synchronized,
it's possible to dock manually.
But you'll stall if your speed
is under 600 km/h.
Where's the G-Fighter pilot?
She's here!
Hurry!
Ah, yes!
This isn't the G-Fighter.
I believe it's the G-Armor.
Can I handle this one?
For someone who's piloted the Gundam...
...it'll be a piece of cake.
Just rely on the machinery.
I'll be watching you from the bridge.
Yes, ma'am. See ya later.
Ms. Sayla! Ready?
I'm still not finished checking. Hold on.
These guys are fast!
The engine output won't increase.
Even if we manage to take off...
Should we have a specialist check it out?
Yes, ma'am!
Fraw Bow! Please ask Lieutenant Matilda
and Colonel Seki to come here!
What's wrong, White Base?
Why haven't you taken off?
The main engine output won't increase.
What? Colonel!
Fraw Bow! How are Amuro and Sayla
doing with the G-Armor?!
It looks like Sayla's having trouble with it.
She can't figure out
the docking process with Gundam!
No time. Tell her to leave it to Amuro,
and just take off...
Ah...
It's fine. Please allow the G-Armor to take off.
Yes... G-Armor. Amuro and Sayla, launch.
Right! Amuro, Ms. Sayla, please take off!
These are for docking...
First, then second...
Ms. Sayla! We're going!
Okay! Go ahead!
Engines at max! Align takeoff axis! Ready?!
Okay!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
To my left?!
Gotcha!
Incoming!
Ms. Sayla! Left!
What?
Ms. Sayla!
In G-Armor mode, your cockpit
has better control of the aircraft!
You can do it!
Is the infrared monitor ready?
I'll be firing the G-Armor's main cannons!
Where's the enemy?
They're behind us! Turn us around!
Roger!
You've gotta pull it harder!
Step on the pedal with all your might!
Too late.
This is tricky.
It's bigger, so it's much harder to turn...
But the G-Armor's beam cannon power
lasts three times longer...
...than the Gundam's. We've got to...
Rotate left, 90 degrees!
I'm aiming the beam cannons.
R-Roger!
Proceed at a 40 degree angle!
Okay. Take this!
I'll swat you, you pesky fly!
I've never seen that one before.
It's not in the Trojan Horse's data, either.
It's a fighter-bomber,
but I've never seen that silhouette before.
Firing rear missiles,
angle minus 4 degrees!
N-Not bad, you mysterious fighter!
There's no problem with
the synchro-motor in itself? That's odd.
No problem here either.
Check it again.
The G-Armor's having trouble in combat.
Both Guncannon and Guntank
are being forced back!
Lieutenant Matilda!
It'll be fine. We can count on Colonel Seki.
Fraw Bow.
Please have my Medea ready
for takeoff at any time.
Ma'am!
We may be just a bit too late.
And what makes you think that?
No particular reason. I somehow feel it.
What is it?
Nothing, ma'am.
You seem to be a chronic worrier.
I suppose I am.
People do tell me that.
Amuro. Sayla. Kai. Hayato.
Hang in there!
There it is!
I'm such a useless klutz!
I can't even slow the enemy down.
He's tough!
Ms. Sayla!
I'm okay! Where are they?!
They've advanced pretty far now.
Please hide us behind the mountain!
You're converting to the Gundam?
Yes!
Will I be able to dock the parts?
I know you can, Ms. Sayla.
That's what you've always
said to me, Ms. Sayla.
So you're returning the favor?
Then I'll give it a try, Amuro.
Pattern G automatic set.
If there's any problem, I will...
No, it'll be just fine! We'll do it!
4... 3... 2...
...1... 0.
Is everything okay, Ms. Sayla?
Yes, the computer did it all for me.
Now, Amuro! Hurry back to the White Base!
Roger!
What? There's a Medea!
It's not Ms. Matilda's Medea, is it?
The pressure has increased
in No. 2 and No. 3.
The rest are no good. In fact,
the pressure seems to be decreasing.
We figured out the problem!
Just give us three minutes!
Please finish it in two minutes!
Fire main cannons!
Fire front missiles horizontally!
Mobile suits?
Found you! I'm putting an end to this!
He dodged my shot!
The vulcans have no effect?!
Oh no! They've reached the White Base!
This Federation mobile suit!
It's not as great as they say!
We're this close to making
the White Base survive this.
I can't sit around and watch it be destroyed.
Take off! Hurry!
Huh? Yes, ma'am!
Oh no! That mobile suit is planning
to destroy the White Base first!
That pilot is no regular guy.
Ortega! Mash!
We're gonna pull a Jet Stream Attack
on that mobile suit!
He's quicker than I thought. Ready?
Yeah!
Is he... coming at me?!
It's working! Let's do the Jet Stream Attack
one more time!
Hm? A Medea? But who's on board?
They're coming...!
Oh no!
He used me as a springboard?!
Drive that Dom into the ground!
Why you...! We almost had that mobile suit!
I-I couldn't do anything to help!
Mash's Dom... destroyed...
That mobile suit slipped
past our Jet Stream Attack...
Unbelievable!
No weapons left.
We need to rethink our tactics, too.
We've got good news.
The White Base repulsed
Zeon's Black Tri-Stars.
It's back on the front lines.
l-ls that so? ...Congratulations.
Well, how about that White Base.
It's proven to be the real thing.
That crew...
How dare they?!
Where do they get their strength from?!
Elran.
Sir?
Operation Odessa,
the attack on M'Quve's base.
It begins at 0600 hours today.
To express our sorrow...
...for the fallen members of Lieutenant Matilda's
Medea transport squadron...
All hands! ...Salute!
This is all because of my inexperience...
I'm so sorry, Ms. Matilda.
Ms. Matilda...
Ms. Matilda!!
MS. MATILDA!!
Before Operation Odessa begins...
...the traitors are discovered and arrested,
leading the Earth Federation to victory.
But the two surviving Black Tri-Star Doms
attack the Gundam relentlessly...
...determined to avenge their fallen comrade.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
The Battle of Odessa.
Next Time
The Battle of Odessa
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...